<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fMRI on Fei</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/tags/fmri/</link><description>Recent content in fMRI on Fei</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flashsherlock.github.io/tags/fmri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>3D-print your brain</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/10/23/how-to-print-your-brain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/10/23/how-to-print-your-brain/</guid><description>1 My little brain 2 Print your brain step-by-step 2.1 Scan your brain 2.2 Reconstruct brain surfaces 2.3 Convert and edit the surfaces 2.4 Refine the brain model and print it 3 Other related tutorials 1 My little brain In this National Day holiday, I made a 3D model of my brain and found a company on Taobao to 3D-print it. The finished product is about 10cm × 9cm × 6.</description></item><item><title>Below-chance accuracy in MVPA</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/09/27/below-chance-accuracy-in-mvpa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/09/27/below-chance-accuracy-in-mvpa/</guid><description>Sometimes, the decoding accuracy of MVPA may lower than chance level, which is confusing. I have found several reasons that may lead to below-chance accuracy in decoding analysis.
special data structure (bias) model parameters (linear vs. non linear) cross validation methods (leave-one-out vs. k-fold) sample size (small vs. large) In short, below-chance accuracy is likely caused by data structure and decoding methods, which can not be simply interpreted as anti-learning.</description></item><item><title>fMRI: Contrast mechanisms and acquisition techniques</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/25/fmri-contrast-mechanisms-and-acquisition-techniques/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/25/fmri-contrast-mechanisms-and-acquisition-techniques/</guid><description>1 Contrast Mechanisms and Acquisition Techniques 1.1 Static Contrasts 1.1.1 Proton-density contrast 1.1.2 T1 contrast 1.1.3 T2 contrast 1.1.4 T2* contrast 1.1.5 Chemical contrast 1.2 Motion Contrasts 1.2.1 MR angiography 1.2.2 Diffusion-weighted contrast 1.2.3 Perfusion-weighted contrast 1.3 Image Acquisition Techniques 1.3.1 Echo-planar imaging 1.3.2 Spiral imaging 1.3.3 Signal recovery and distortion correction for EPI and spiral images 1.3.4 Parallel imaging -- 1 Contrast Mechanisms and Acquisition Techniques Two primary types of contrast are used in MRI.</description></item><item><title>fMRI: Basic principles of image formation</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/23/fmri-basic-principles-of-image-formation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/23/fmri-basic-principles-of-image-formation/</guid><description>1 MR Image Formation 1.1 Analysis of the MR Signal 1.1.1 Longitudinal magnetization (\(M_z\)) 1.1.2 Transverse magnetization (\(M_{xy}\)) 1.1.3 The MR signal equation 1.2 Image Reconstruction 1.2.1 Slice selection 1.2.2 Frequency and phase encoding 1.2.3 Relationship between image space and k-space 1.2.4 Converting from k-space to image space 1.3 3-D Imaging 1.4 Potential Problems in Image Formation 1.4.1 Inhomogeneity of the static magnetic field 1.4.2 nonlinearities in the gradient fields 1 MR Image Formation 1.</description></item><item><title>fMRI: Basic principles of signal generation</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/18/fmri-basic-principles-of-signal-generation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/18/fmri-basic-principles-of-signal-generation/</guid><description>1 MR Signal Generation 1.1 Magnetic Moment 1.2 Angular Momentum 1.3 Spins in an External Magnetic Field 1.4 Energy Difference between Parallel and Antiparallel States 1.5 Magnetization of a Spin System 1.6 Excitation of a Spin System and Signal Reception 1.6.1 Spin excitation 1.6.2 Signal reception 1.7 Relaxation Mechanisms of a Spin System 1.8 The Bloch Equation for MR Signal Generation 2 Basic Principles of MR Image Formation 2.</description></item></channel></rss>