<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>reading on Fei</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/categories/reading/</link><description>Recent content in reading on Fei</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flashsherlock.github.io/categories/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>fMRI: Contrast mechanisms and acquisition techniques</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/25/fmri-contrast-mechanisms-and-acquisition-techniques/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/25/fmri-contrast-mechanisms-and-acquisition-techniques/</guid><description>1 Contrast Mechanisms and Acquisition Techniques 1.1 Static Contrasts 1.1.1 Proton-density contrast 1.1.2 T1 contrast 1.1.3 T2 contrast 1.1.4 T2* contrast 1.1.5 Chemical contrast 1.2 Motion Contrasts 1.2.1 MR angiography 1.2.2 Diffusion-weighted contrast 1.2.3 Perfusion-weighted contrast 1.3 Image Acquisition Techniques 1.3.1 Echo-planar imaging 1.3.2 Spiral imaging 1.3.3 Signal recovery and distortion correction for EPI and spiral images 1.3.4 Parallel imaging -- 1 Contrast Mechanisms and Acquisition Techniques Two primary types of contrast are used in MRI.</description></item><item><title>fMRI: Basic principles of image formation</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/23/fmri-basic-principles-of-image-formation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/23/fmri-basic-principles-of-image-formation/</guid><description>1 MR Image Formation 1.1 Analysis of the MR Signal 1.1.1 Longitudinal magnetization (\(M_z\)) 1.1.2 Transverse magnetization (\(M_{xy}\)) 1.1.3 The MR signal equation 1.2 Image Reconstruction 1.2.1 Slice selection 1.2.2 Frequency and phase encoding 1.2.3 Relationship between image space and k-space 1.2.4 Converting from k-space to image space 1.3 3-D Imaging 1.4 Potential Problems in Image Formation 1.4.1 Inhomogeneity of the static magnetic field 1.4.2 nonlinearities in the gradient fields 1 MR Image Formation 1.</description></item><item><title>fMRI: Basic principles of signal generation</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/18/fmri-basic-principles-of-signal-generation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/08/18/fmri-basic-principles-of-signal-generation/</guid><description>1 MR Signal Generation 1.1 Magnetic Moment 1.2 Angular Momentum 1.3 Spins in an External Magnetic Field 1.4 Energy Difference between Parallel and Antiparallel States 1.5 Magnetization of a Spin System 1.6 Excitation of a Spin System and Signal Reception 1.6.1 Spin excitation 1.6.2 Signal reception 1.7 Relaxation Mechanisms of a Spin System 1.8 The Bloch Equation for MR Signal Generation 2 Basic Principles of MR Image Formation 2.</description></item><item><title>Ten rules for ERP experiments</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/18/rules-for-experiments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/18/rules-for-experiments/</guid><description>Rules In the chapter &amp;ldquo;Ten Simple Rules for Designing and Interpreting ERP Experiments&amp;rdquo; of the book Event-Related Potentials: A Methods Handbook, Steven J. Luck proposed ten rules for ERP experiments.
Peaks and components are not the same thing. There is nothing special about the point at which the voltage reaches a local maximum or minimum.
It is impossible to estimate the time course or peak latency of a latent ERP component by looking at a single ERP waveform – there may be no obvious relationship between the shape of a local part of the waveform and the underlying latent components.</description></item></channel></rss>