<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>R on Fei</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/categories/r/</link><description>Recent content in R on Fei</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flashsherlock.github.io/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ggplot2: Extending ggplot2</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/04/05/ggplot2-extending-ggplot2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/04/05/ggplot2-extending-ggplot2/</guid><description>1 Programming with ggplot2 1.1 Single components 1.2 Multiple components 1.3 Plot functions 1.4 Functional programming 2 ggplot2 internals 2.1 The plot() method 2.2 The build step 2.3 The gtable step 2.4 Introducing ggproto 3 Writing ggplot2 extensions 3.1 New themes 3.2 New stats 3.3 New geoms 3.4 New coords 3.5 New scales 3.6 New positions 3.7 New facets 1 Programming with ggplot2 To make your code more flexible, you need to reduce duplicated code by writing functions.</description></item><item><title>ggplot2: The grammar</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/04/02/ggplot2-the-grammar/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/04/02/ggplot2-the-grammar/</guid><description>1 Inroduction 2 Build a plot layer by layer 2.1 Data 2.2 Aesthetic mappings 2.3 Geoms 2.4 Stats 2.5 Position adjustments 3 Scales and guides 3.1 Scale transformation 3.2 Scale guides 3.3 Scale breaks 3.4 Legend merging and splitting 4 Coordinate systems 4.1 Linear coordinate systems 4.2 Non-linear coordinate systems 5 Faceting 5.1 Facet wrap 5.2 Facet grid 5.3 Controlling scales 5.4 Missing faceting variables 6 Themes 6.1 Complete themes 6.</description></item><item><title>ggplot2: Scales</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/03/30/ggplot2-scales/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/03/30/ggplot2-scales/</guid><description>1 Introduction 2 Position scales and axes 2.1 Numeric 2.2 Date-time 2.3 Discrete 2.4 Binned 2.5 Limits 3 Color scales and legends 3.1 Continuous color scales 3.2 Discrete color scales 3.3 Alpha scales 3.4 Legends 4 Other aesthetics 4.1 Size 4.2 Shape 4.3 Line type 4.4 Manual scales 4.5 Identity scales 1 Introduction The scales toolbox divide scales into three main groups:
Position scales and axes. Color scales and legends.</description></item><item><title>ggplot2: Getting started</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/03/29/ggplot2-getting-started/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/03/29/ggplot2-getting-started/</guid><description>1 Introduction 2 Getting started 2.1 Aesthetic attributes 2.2 Faceting 2.3 Plot geoms 2.4 Modifying the axes 2.5 Output 1 Introduction The book ggplot2: Elegant Graphics for Data Analysis is a good starting point for learning ggplot2, a useful R package for producing graphics. I summarized some main points and useful tips here. For more details, please refer to the online version of the book. Packages required for this book are listed below.</description></item><item><title>ggplot2: Layers</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/03/29/ggplot2-layers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2021/03/29/ggplot2-layers/</guid><description>1 Introduction 2 Geoms 3 Statistical summaries 3.1 Revealing uncertainty 3.2 Weighted data 3.3 Displaying distributions 3.4 Dealing with overplotting 3.5 Statistical summaries 3.6 Surfaces 4 Annotations 4.1 Plot and axis titles 4.2 Text labels 4.3 Building custom annotations 5 Arranging plots 1 Introduction In general, there are three purposes for a layer:
To display the data. To display a statistical summary of the data. To add additional metadata: context, annotations, and references.</description></item><item><title>Read xls files using gdata package in R</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/06/read-xls-files/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/06/read-xls-files/</guid><description>Openxlsx package can read xlsx files, but not xls files. To read xlsx files that contain time records for the online course videos, gdata package should be used.
filename &amp;lt;- dir(pattern = &amp;quot;*.xls&amp;quot;) results &amp;lt;- data.frame(row.names = c(&amp;quot;click_times&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;times&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;class&amp;quot;)) for (f in filename) { all_data &amp;lt;- read.xls(f) my_data &amp;lt;- subset(all_data,all_data[2]==&amp;quot;2019******005&amp;quot;,select = c(3,4)) if (nrow(my_data)) { all_data &amp;lt;- cbind(my_data,substring(f,3,5)) results &amp;lt;- rbind(results,all_data) } # extract hours minutes and seconds times &amp;lt;- strsplit(as.</description></item><item><title>Demo Markdown</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/02/demo-markdown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/02/demo-markdown/</guid><description>This is a post written in plain Markdown (*.md) instead of R Markdown (*.Rmd). The major differences are:
You cannot run any R code in a plain Markdown document, whereas in an R Markdown document, you can embed R code chunks (```{r}); A plain Markdown post is rendered through Blackfriday, and an R Markdown document is compiled by rmarkdown and Pandoc. There are many differences in syntax between Blackfriday&amp;rsquo;s Markdown and Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s Markdown.</description></item><item><title>Hello R Markdown</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/02/hello-r-markdown/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/02/hello-r-markdown/</guid><description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description></item></channel></rss>