<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>paper on Fei</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/tags/paper/</link><description>Recent content in paper on Fei</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flashsherlock.github.io/tags/paper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Poster for ISOT2024</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2024/06/20/poster-for-isot2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2024/06/20/poster-for-isot2024/</guid><description>1 Abstract Scents trigger diverse changes in our moods and feelings. These effects are commonly ascribed to the privileged access of odors to the amygdala, yet the underlying mechanisms remain elusive. Utilizing a high-resolution multi-electrode array, we conducted systematic local field potential (LFP) recordings in the amygdala complex and anterior hippocampus of anesthetized macaques under repetitive exposures to various odors. We observed significant olfactory modulations of the spectral powers of rhythmic activities and their phase couplings with the respiratory cycle in the amygdala, but not the adjacent hippocampus.</description></item><item><title>Ten rules for ERP experiments</title><link>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/18/rules-for-experiments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://flashsherlock.github.io/2020/05/18/rules-for-experiments/</guid><description>Rules In the chapter &amp;ldquo;Ten Simple Rules for Designing and Interpreting ERP Experiments&amp;rdquo; of the book Event-Related Potentials: A Methods Handbook, Steven J. Luck proposed ten rules for ERP experiments.
Peaks and components are not the same thing. There is nothing special about the point at which the voltage reaches a local maximum or minimum.
It is impossible to estimate the time course or peak latency of a latent ERP component by looking at a single ERP waveform – there may be no obvious relationship between the shape of a local part of the waveform and the underlying latent components.</description></item></channel></rss>